Richard Bustos

Engineer | Advocate | Leader

3 650-888-1411

→ Hello@richbustos.com

www.richbustos.com

San Francisco, CA



Passionate engineer for over 5+ years to help build delightful products. I write code, craft UX designs, advocate/build relationships with communities, and much more.

On my spare time you can typically find me reading up on the latest movies news, hiking while getting lost in the wild, posting my adventures on IG, and assist coaching for the El Camino Wrestling team in South San Francisco.

WORK EXPERIENCES

Frontend Engineer | Developer Advocate

Wix | Aug 2021 - Nov 2022

One of the founding Developer Advocates to join Velo, a full-stack development platform that empowers you to rapidly build, manage and deploy professional web apps.

Software Engineer, Frontend

LinkedIn | Dec 2019 - Aug 2021

I went back to LinkedIn to work on a project called "Underconnected Youth". This project entails creating economic opportunity for every underconnected youth in the world.

Design Technologist (UI/Frontend)

KeepTruckin | Mar 2019 - Dec 2019

A crossbreed of front-end engineering and design. I lead our in-house design system, called SprayShop! After successfully delivering, we continued to build out features and components by crafting and evangelizing KeepTruckin's design system to help UI engineers build a consistent look and feel across all products.

Software Engineer, Frontend

LinkedIn | Aug 2013 - Mar 2019

I've worked on multiple projects and served multiple teams.

Teams included: Homepage, Feed, Messaging, Growth, Horizontal, Email, and Brand & Marketing.

Web Developer Internship

LinkedIn | Dec 2012 - Aug 2013

I earned an amazing internship with the telecommunication team on the Global Technology Solution department, also known as the IT of LinkedIn. I was continuously learning and growing new skills during this internship.

Content Writer & Developer

ComiConverse | 2015 - 2016

I served as a writer who discussed television shows and movies in the superhero realm! This includes: re-capping on latest episodes, movie reviews, news on film casting, and much more! As part of this small amazing team I will also focus on enhancing the look and feel to the website (built on Wordpress).

Javascript Teaching Assistant

Year Up | 2014

Assisted the course instructor on teaching the fundamentals of JavaScript to a class of 20+ students from the Year Up Silicon Valley site.By the end of the 12-week session, students will have developed an interactive game in the browser utilizing JavaScript, HTML, CSS, and Canvas. Students will also learn troubleshooting methods such as debugging through the console and using inspector tools in Google Chrome.

SKILLS

Technical

HTML/HTML5

CSS/SASS/SCSS

Javascript

React.js, Ember.js, Vue.js

Scala, Java

Tools

Sublime lira

Notion Sketch

Google Docs Figma Google Sheets

EDUCATION

Computer Programming

Stanford

2012-2014

General Education

Skyline College

2011 - 2012

Awards

Hackday Winner (LinkedIn) Dean's List of Academic Scholar

Hobbies

Photography/Videography

Crypto/Web3

Travelling

Meditation & Mindfulness



